pronurse.co.uk 2010-12-30

# - ProNurse.co.uk

**Your Privacy Rights**

Monster is committed to protecting the privacy of our users, and strives to provide a safe, secure user experience. This Privacy Statement sets forth the online data collection and usage policies and practises that apply to this web site. It does not apply to information we collect in any other fashion.

Your access to, and use of, this Web site and your provision of any personal information to Monster via this Web site constitutes your acceptance, without limitation or qualification, of the collection, use and transfer of the personal information provided by you in the manner described in this Statement. Please read this Statement carefully as it affects your rights and liabilities under law. If you disagree with the way we collect and process personal information collected on the Web site, we recommend that you do not use it.

**Scope of this Policy**

This statement applies to ProNurse.co.uk which is owned and operated by Monster Worldwide Limited ("Monster"), or by Monster-affiliated companies (the "Site" or "Sites"). "Affiliated companies" means entities that control, are controlled by or are under common control with Monster, Inc. Monster complies with data protection legislation. This regulates the processing of information relating to you and grants you various rights in respect to your personal data.

The sites contain links to other web sites over which we have no control. Monster is not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of other web sites to which you choose to link from this site. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of those other web sites so you can understand how they collect, use and share your information.

**Information We Collect and Retain**

You do not have to give us any personal information in order to perform job searches or to read the content portions of our Site. However, you will need an account, for such activities as uploading photos or video, participating in forums, creating a profile, and chatting with other members. We collect the following general types of information about you when you visit our Sites: personal information, demographic information, behavioural information, and indirect information. Sometimes we collect combinations of all these types of information. In each case, it is indicated on the web site whether any personal or demographic data must be provided to use the requested service or not.

_Personal information_ is information that can be used to identify you personally. We do not collect personal information unless you choose to provide it to us. You do not need to provide personal information to create an account on ProNurse. To create an account on ProNurse, you need to provide us with:

  * · Username, which may be self-chosen to preserve your anonymity 
  * · Email address 
  * · Career status 
  * · Type of service 
  * · Postal code 
  * · Password 

Should you choose to apply for a job online, you will be redirected to the Monster Sites, and your information will become subject to Monster’s privacy policy. Some examples of personal information that we collect in the job areas of Monster are:

  * · Your name 
  * · Address 
  * · Email address 
  * · Telephone number 
  * · Credit card number 
  * · Contact information 
  * · Billing information 
  * · Information about third parties, such as references or contacts, that you provide to us if you have their express written consent to do so. 

_Demographic information_ is information that is not unique to you, such as your ZIP (postal) code, age, preferences, gender, race or ethnicity, occupation, career history, interests and favourites.

We also collect _behavioural information_ regarding how you use our sites, the areas of our site that you visit, what services you access, and information about your computer hardware and software including your IP address, geolocation, browser and operating system type, domain names, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is necessary for analysing the use of resources, troubleshooting problems, preventing fraud, and improving our services.

**How Information is Used**

We use the information we gather on the web site for the purposes of providing our services, responding to any queries you may have, operating and improving the web site, fostering a positive user experience and delivering the products and services that we offer to jobseekers and employers. Our services include the display of personalized products, content, and advertising relating to your career experience and interests.

The information we gather on any Monster web site when you apply for a job may be shared within the Monster group of companies on a worldwide basis in order to deliver these products and services.

If you have consented for us to do so, or if permitted by applicable law, we may use your information in the following ways:

  * · to allow you to create an account; 
  * · to create a profile for you based on information that you have provided to us; 
  * · to contact you about ProNurse updates, informational and service-related communications, including important security updates; 
  * · to provide you additional communications, information, and promotions such as newsletters and career advice; 
  * · to inform you of other products or services available from Monster or its affiliates; 
  * · to enable you to provide feedback, to contact us and for us to respond to you; 
  * · to conduct surveys, questionnaires, promotions and contests, and to provide the results thereof such as success stories and contest winners; 
  * · to generate internal reports about the use of our site; 
  * · to provide products and services that enable users to network, post information on bulletin boards, view and compare profiles, and career background and experience; and 
  * · to provide ‘forward to a friend’ features. 

In addition to these uses, if you apply for a job through our site, the Monster Site may use your information as follows:

  * · to provide information about you and your potential interest in job postings to employer customers; and 
  * · to provide products and services to employer customers to complete the recruitment and hiring process, such as accessing the searchable CV database. 

Some of our products and services, such as Monster’s searchable CV database and ProNurse’s networking areas, enable third parties to see your personal information and to contact you. Profile information may be used for networking with other community members or may be visible to employers who are using the Monster Sites. In addition, portions of your searchable CV (but not your contact information) may be made public in your networking profile.

**Information you post in public areas of the site or placed in the searchable CV database will be accessed, used, and stored by others around the world.**

By providing your personal information for inclusion in our database, you acknowledge that you consent to your information being used as described here. While Monster takes measures to safeguard your information from unauthorised access or inappropriate use by third parties, Monster does not control these third parties and we are not responsible for their use of information you post or otherwise make available in public areas of ProNurse or the Monster Sites. Accordingly, you should ensure that you do not post sensitive information to any of our site.

**Disclosure of Information to Others**

We disclose to third parties your personal information, combined personal, demographic, behavioural or indirect information, as set forth below.

1\. We may share your information with third parties who help us in the delivery of our own products and services to you. We disclose information to companies and individuals we employ to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include hosting our web servers, analysing data, providing marketing assistance, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. We also use Google Analytics, a tool which sends aggregated anonymous user data to Google U.S.

These companies and individuals may be located in a country whose data protection legislation is different from that of your country, and they will have access to your personal information as necessary to perform their functions, but they may not share that information with any other third party or use that data for any other purpose. We will remain the data controller and be responsible for any information shared in this way.

2\. We may disclose such information to third parties if you consent to such disclosure. For example, if you indicate that you would like to receive information about the opportunities, products or services of third parties, we supply your contact information to select third parties such as employers, recruiters, data aggregators, marketers or others for the purpose of sending you e-mail or otherwise communicating with you. We use data we have about you (such as the interests and preferences you have expressed) to determine whether you might be interested in the opportunities, products or services of a particular third party. If you make your CV searchable, then all parties with access to Monster’s searchable CV database (or copies thereof) will have access to that database.

We also share aggregated anonymous information about visitors to the Sites with clients, partners, other site visitors, and other third parties so that they can understand the kinds of visitors to the Sites and how those visitors use the Sites. We may also aggregate on an anonymous basis data regarding job qualifications, schooling, age, experience level or other information relevant to the job search or competition among job seekers for any such job. Such data may be made available to employers or fellow job seekers or community members.

Monster supplies technology, hosting and related services to other leading companies to power recruitment areas on their Web sites (sometimes referred to as "Hosted Career Sites"). Personal and/or demographic information supplied by you in Hosted Career Sites becomes part of the Monster database, but it is not accessible by anyone other than you, Monster, and the company concerned without your consent. If you attempt to register with Monster after registering with a Hosted Career Site, Monster will recognise your information and you will be able to use the information you provided to the Hosted Career Site in your account registration.

Information gathered on a page in a hosted career site area or on a co-branded page may be retained by both Monster and the other company. In that instance, the use of such information by the other company will be subject to the privacy policy of that company and Monster is not responsible for that company's use of your personal or demographic information.

If you apply for a position through a hosted career site or a co-branded site, you may be asked to provide information on your age, gender or race where permitted by law. You should understand that, if provided, this information should only be used by employers in accordance with applicable law. However, Monster is not responsible for the actions of such employers. All such information provided will be kept separate by Monster from your expression of interest in any job opportunity. Providing this information is strictly voluntary and you will not be subject to any adverse action or treatment from Monster if you choose not to provide this information.

3\. We disclose information if legally required to do so, if requested to do so by a governmental entity or if we believe in good faith that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process; (b) protect our rights or property or our affiliated companies; (c) prevent a crime or protect national security; or (d) protect the personal safety of users or the public. Because information collected on the Monster site is stored in whole or in part in the United States, it may become subject to U.S. law.

4\. We may disclose and transfer such information to a third party who acquires all or a substantial portion of Monster's business, whether such acquisition is by way of merger, consolidation or purchase of all or a substantial portion of our assets. In addition, in the event Monster becomes the subject of an insolvency proceeding, whether voluntary or involuntary, Monster or its liquidator, administrator, receiver or administrative receiver may sell, license or otherwise dispose of such information in a transaction approved by the court. You will be notified of sale of all or a substantial portion of our business to a third party by email or through a prominent notice posted on the Sites.

**An Important Note about Your CV**

When you create or post a CV to the Monster site, that CV is stored in our searchable CV database in the United States. You may control the status of your CV by setting it to private or public.

If you set your CV as private, it is not searchable by potential employers or other with access to our CV database. You may still use your CV to apply online to a job. **If you do apply online to a job, your CV will be transferred to the relevant employer, who may retain a copy of your CV or distribute it to third parties.** We are not responsible for their use and retention of your CV information.

If you set your CV as public, but want your contact information to be confidential, your CV will be searchable by potential employers, but we will hide your contact information and current company. You must also remove your contact information from your uploaded or copy and paste text CV. You should be aware that if you have a rare skill or job title, for example, it may still be possible for you to be identified even without your contact details being included. If you are worried about being identified, you should not include specific details by which you could be identified. **If you use a confidential CV to apply to a job online, the employer to whom you send your CV will be able to view your contact information in order to contact you about your application.**

If you allow your CV to be searchable without making it confidential, then all parties with access to our searchable CV database (or copies thereof) will have access to your CV. Employers or other parties with access to our searchable CV database may be located in countries whose data protection legislation may not equivalent to the laws in your country. For example, your CV may be viewed and accessed by employers outside the European Economic Area who have access to our searchable database. By making your CV searchable, you are expressly consenting to such transfers of data occurring.

**We attempt to limit access to our searchable CV database to legitimate users such as paying employers, recruiters, hiring managers, headhunters and human resource professionals, as well as law enforcement and national security agencies, but cannot guarantee that other parties will not gain access to this database.**

We are not responsible for the use made of CVs by third parties who access such CVs while they are in our searchable database. You may remove your CV from our searchable database at any time; details of how to do this are given below. However, employers, recruiters and others who have paid for access to that database, as well as parties who have otherwise gained access to the database may have retained a copy of your CV in their own files or databases. We are not responsible for the retention, use or privacy of CVs or profiles that have been downloaded by third parties. Accordingly, you should not put sensitive information, or other information you would not want made public in your CV.

If you provide us with details of a reference, it is your responsibility to ensure that the person is aware that you have forwarded his/her details and has consented in writing for you to do so.

If you use our facilities to build a CV or to post a CV in our database of jobseekers’ CVs, then you will be providing us with personal data we will use in accordance with this Statement. Your CV should not contain data relating to your (i) racial or ethnic origin (ii) political beliefs (iii) philosophical or religious beliefs (iv) membership of a trade union or political party (v) physical or mental health (vi) sexual life (vii) the commission of criminal offences or proceedings, or (vii) any national identification number. If your CV does contain such data, then you agree that we may retain this information and use it in accordance with this Statement. We are not responsible for third parties’ access to such information from our searchable database.

**Posting to Your Information Public Areas**

Please remember that if you post any of your personal information in public areas of ProNurse or on Monster, such as in online forums or chat rooms, or in the searchable CV database, such information may be collected and used by others over whom we have no control. We are not responsible for the use made by third parties of information you post or otherwise make available in public areas of ProNurse or Monster.

**Your Choices About Your Information**

Because managing your career is a life-long process, we retain all the information we gather about you in an effort to make your repeat use with us more efficient, practical and relevant until you change or remove your personal data as described below. You may have access to, review, correct, update, change or delete your account profile information or CV at any time. Simply log into your account, go to your profile or CV, and make the necessary changes. You may delete your CV from Monster’s online database at any time by accessing your account there. Before providing you with a copy of your personal information or correcting, updating or deleting such information, we reserve the right to verify and authenticate your identity and the personal information to which you have requested access. Access to or correction, updating or deletion of your personal information may be denied or limited if it is unreasonably burdensome or expensive to so under the circumstances, if it would violate another person’s rights and/or as otherwise permitted by applicable law.

If you wish to delete or close your ProNurse or Monster account or account profile information altogether, please contact us by clicking here. An email will be sent to you to confirm that your personal information has been deleted (save for an archival copy which is not accessible by you or third parties on the Internet). The archival copy is retained indefinitely for audit and record purposes. We will retain logs, demographic, indirect, and statistical information about you and keep an archival copy of this information in an anonymised form. If your personal information was previously accessed by others using our Sites, we are not able to delete the information or copies thereof from their systems.

If you are a job seeker and have not logged onto the Monster web site for 18 months, then we will automatically make your CV unsearchable.

If you wish to revoke your consent to our Privacy Statement, please click here. However, please note that if you do withdraw your consent, you may not be able to use the relevant services and your account and profile information will be deleted.

If you previously opted to receive newsletters, commercial e-mails or other communications from Monster or third parties, but subsequently change your mind, you may opt-out by editing your account profile as described above. If you previously opted not to receive such communications, you may later opt-in by editing your account profile.

**Important Information**

**_Security_**

You are responsible for ensuring that your log-in credentials (your username and password) are kept confidential.

Monster has implemented technical and organisational measures designed to secure your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorised access, use, alteration or disclosure. Notwithstanding such measures, the Internet is an open system and we cannot guarantee that unauthorised third parties will never be able to defeat those measures or use your personal information for improper purposes. Moreover, one of our primary purposes is to provide you with a platform to broadcast the information in your CV and profile widely and to maximise your networking and career opportunities. Accordingly, such an environment does present a risk that unauthorised third parties will view this data, so you should refer to our Security Centre for additional information on conducting a safe job search. Further, your CV should not contain any sensitive data or data which you would not want made public. You should be aware that CV’s you complete at your current place of work may be monitored by your current employer.

When you place an order online at Monster, your credit card information is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer ("SSL") protocol. SSL makes it difficult for your credit card information to be intercepted or stolen while being transmitted. Monster uses a service company to process its credit card transactions. For further information on this company’s privacy and security practices, please click here.

We also use cookies, web beacons, and Java Script to administer our site and deliver a personalized experience. For additional detailed information on each of these, please see below.

**_Children_**

Monster is not intended for, nor do we knowingly collect information from, children under the age of 18.

**_Safe Harbor_**

Monster participates in the US Department of Commerce's Safe Harbor Framework arising out of the U.S. implementation of the European Union Data Protection Directive. Monster Worldwide Inc., Monster, Inc. and Monster Worldwide Technologies LLC have certified adherence to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles for each of the Monster sites. For more information about the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles and to view our certification, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's Safe Harbor web site. If you would like to contact us directly about the Safe Harbor program, please send an e-mail to privacystatement@monster.com.

Monster Worldwide, Inc., Monster, Inc, and Monster Technologies, Inc. are members of the TRUSTe privacy seal program, the TRUSTe E.U. Safe harbor seal program and the TRUSTe dispute resolution program. Please consult the TRUSTe Web site http://www.truste.com for more information concerning TRUSTe’s privacy programs and dispute resolution procedures. The TRUSTe programs cover only information collected through Monster.com, and does not cover information that may be collected through ProNurse.co.uk or software downloaded from the Sites.

**Changes to Privacy Statement**

If we decide to change the substance of our Privacy Statement, we will post those changes through a prominent notice on the web site so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and to whom we will disclose it.

**Legal and Contact Information**

Your data is submitted to Monster Worldwide Limited, but if you apply for a job, your data is hosted and stored in a database on servers situated in the United States owned and maintained by Monster Worldwide Technologies LLC, a Delaware corporation whose principal place of business is at 622 Third Avenue, New York 10017, New York, USA. Monster, Inc. a Delaware corporation with its principal place of business at 5 Clock Tower Place, Maynard, MA 01754, USA is the legal entity determining the purposes and means of processing the information gathered at the Sites and is the data controller of all data stored in the Monster database; however Monster Worldwide Limited is also a data controller in relation to your personal data provided to ProNurse.co.uk.

If, at any time, you have questions or concerns about this Privacy Statement or believe that we have not adhered to this Privacy Statement, please feel free to email us at info@monster.co.uk or contact us at Monster.co.uk at Chancery House, 53-64 Chancery Lane, London, WC2A 1QS.

We will use reasonable efforts to answer promptly your question or resolve your problem. If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry, or if your inquiry is not satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact privacystatement@monster.com, Monster Worldwide, Inc., 5 Clocktower Place, Suite 500, Maynard, MA. 01754, USA. to resolve your concerns. If your question is not properly addressed, you may contact TRUSTe.

**Use of Cookies, Web Beacons, and Java Script**

**_Cookies_** : ProNurse and Monster use "cookies" to help personalise and maximise your online experience and time online. A cookie is a text file that is either stored in your computer’s memory temporarily (a "session" cookie) or placed on your hard drive (a "persistent" cookie) by a Web page server. Cookies are not used to run programmes or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to your computer and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

When you return to the site, cookies enable us to retrieve the information you previously provided, so you can easily use the features that you customised. Because of our use of cookies, we can deliver faster and more accurate results and a more personalised site experience. For example, if you personalise Monster pages, or register for services, a cookie helps us to recall your specific information (such as user name, password and preferences).

ProNurse predominantly uses a persistent login cookie that allows you to return to the site to be automatically logged in. Monster predominately uses "session" cookies which are not permanently stored on your hard drive.

Session cookies expire after two hours of inactivity or when you close your browser. When you carry out a job search or apply online a large amount of data is processed by our system and transferred through each page of the search or application process. This information includes your job search criteria, data that identifies your CV, covering letter, the job you are applying for, your right to work in the relevant country and the results of any questionnaire you have completed as part of the online application process as well as demographic information that is not unique to you. "Session" cookies allow us to keep track of this data until you have completed your search or application. We also use cookies to identify users who have been banned from using our forums for behaviour that contradicts our terms of use and to track click streams, for load balancing and to enable you to navigate through the site using redirection pages.

We use "persistent" cookies primarily to ensure that we do not show you pages that you have already seen and to personalise your site experience and save you time. "Persistent" cookies enable us to recognise whether you have responded to any poll or seen an advertisement or information notice placed on the site so that we do not show you the poll, advertisement or notice again the next time you visit our site. If you are a recruiter and have an alliance arrangement in place with Monster we also use "persistent" cookies to recall your alliance status and display your correct pricing information when you access our site. If you register on our site by using your Microsoft Passport user name and password a "persistent" cookie allows us to access and store information in your Passport account profile so you can login to our site faster. This information is treated in accordance with the policies and practices described in our Privacy Statement above. The "persistent" cookies we use will remain on your computer after you have left ProNurse after 1 year and Monster’s site and will expire when you log out of the Site or 60 days after your last visit for security cookies, 90 days after your last visit for poll response and alliance cookies, one year after your last visit for Microsoft Passport user cookies or two years after your last visit for advertisement and information notice cookies.

We also allow other companies to serve advertisements to you. Because your web browser must request these advertisements from the other companies’ servers, these companies can view, edit or set their own cookies, just as if you had requested a web page from their site. Monster has no control over, and is not responsible for, the practices of those third party advertisers. Monster encourages you to review the policies of such advertisers. We allow persistent third party cookies as part of online advertising campaigns to determine and track site traffic landing from Monster’s advertising banners that have been placed on the websites of third parties. The data collected via these cookies is anonymous and the information is not personally identifiable. The "persistent" cookies placed by our third party ad servers will remain on your computer after you have left our site for up to 20 years. You will find additional information about our third party ad servers at www2.doubleclick.com/uk/privacy and www.atlassolutions.com/privacy.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies at any time by modifying your browser settings. See the end of this Privacy Statement for instructions.. If you choose to decline cookies, however, that may hinder performance and negatively impact your experience on the web site.

**_Web Beacons:_** ProNurse and Monster Web pages may also contain electronic images known as Web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel gifs) that allow us to count users who have visited those pages and to deliver co-branded services. Web beacons are not used to access your personally identifiable information on Monster; they are a technique we use to compile aggregated statistics about our web site usage. Web beacons collect only a limited set of information including a cookie number, time and date of a page view, and a description of the page on which the Web beacon resides.

Because Web beacons are the same as any other content request included in the recipe page, you cannot opt out or refuse them. However, they can be rendered ineffective by either opting out of cookies or changing the cookie setup in your browser. Third parties are not permitted to use web beacons on the Monster sites.

**_JavaScript:_** ProNurse may also use JavaScript, for example, within certain advertisements. JavaScript is a script language that enhances the functionality of websites, particularly in respect to pictures. We are not collecting any personal data via JavaScript but use it to inform employers about how many applicants have clicked on email addresses embedded in their job ads, for example. You may deactivate JavaScript via your browser settings or activate it the same way. If you disable JavaScript you will not be able to use some of the functions of the website.

**How to Choose Your Preferred Cookie Settings in Your Web Browser**

The main browser types are listed below. If you have a different browser type, please refer to the ‘Help’ file or your handbook.

**Windows PC**

**Internet Explorer 7.0**

Choose Tools and then Internet Options

Click the Privacy tab

Move the slider to choose your preferred settings.

For more specialized cookie settings, click on “Advanced”

**Internet Explorer 6.0**

Choose Tools and then Internet Options

Click the Privacy tab

Move the slider to choose your preferred settings

The default setting is medium and the menu allows you to select the level of "filtering" on the basis of (a) the source of the cookie and (b) whether the source has a privacy policy 

For more specialized cookie settings click on “Advanced”

**Mozilla Firebox 3.0**

Click on the Tools Menu

Select Options

Select the Privacy panel and choose your preferred settings

**Mozilla Firefox 2.0**

Click on Tools, then Options (or Edit | Preferences on Linux)

Select the Privacy icon in the left-hand panel

Click on Cookies.

Choose your preferred settings.

Note that the option to block third-party cookies has been removed from Firefox 2's user interface. Firefox 2 users who wish to limit allowed cookies to those set by the originating website can use about:config to modify the preference network.cookie.cookieBehavior to "1". To modify this property simply type "about:config" (without quotes) in the Location Bar, press Enter and modify the value in the resulting page.

Other options for the network.cookie.cookieBehavior preference are set out below:

"0" All cookies are allowed. (Default)

"1" Only cookies from the originating server are allowed.

"2" No cookies are allowed.

**Mozilla Firefox 1.5**

Click on Tools, then Options (or Edit | Preferences on Linux)

Select the Privacy icon in the left-hand panel

Click on Cookies.

Choose your preferred settings (You can configure which sites are allowed to set cookies, how long to keep them for, and view and manage your existing cookies.)

**Mozilla Firefox 1.0**

Click on Tools, then Options

Select the Privacy icon in the left-hand panel

Click on Cookies.

Choose your preferred settings.

**Netscape Navigator 7**

Choose Preferences from the Edit menu.

Select Privacy & Security, then select Cookies.

Choose your preferred settings.

**Netscape Navigator 6**

Choose Preferences from the Edit menu.

Select Privacy & Security, then select Cookies.

Choose your preferred settings.

**Opera**

Click on the File menu on the Opera tool bar

Go to Preferences at the bottom of the File menu

Click Privacy and select one of the available options

**Safari 1.0 (MacOS X)**

Choose Preferences from Safari menu

Select Security icon

Cookie settings are shown in window

Choose your preferred settings

**Update effective 1 September 2008**
